export const history = [
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Which%20one%20of%20these%20was%20not%20a%20beach%20landing%20site%20in%20the%20Invasion%20of%20Normandy%3F",
    correct_answer: "Silver",
    incorrect_answers: ["Gold", "Juno", "Sword"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "King%20Henry%20VIII%20was%20the%20second%20monarch%20of%20which%20European%20royal%20house%3F",
    correct_answer: "Tudor",
    incorrect_answers: ["York", "Stuart", "Lancaster"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "What%20was%20William%20Frederick%20Cody%20better%20known%20as%3F",
    correct_answer: "Buffalo%20Bill",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "Billy%20the%20Kid",
      "Wild%20Bill%20Hickok",
      "Pawnee%20Bill",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Which%20German%20field%20marshal%20was%20known%20as%20the%20%60Desert%20Fox%60%3F",
    correct_answer: "Erwin%20Rommel",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "Ernst%20Busch",
      "Wolfram%20Freiherr%20von%20Richthofen",
      "Wilhelm%20List",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "Who%20discovered%20Penicillin%3F",
    correct_answer: "Alexander%20Flemming",
    incorrect_answers: ["Marie%20Curie", "Alfred%20Nobel", "Louis%20Pasteur"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "How%20many%20manned%20moon%20landings%20have%20there%20been%3F",
    correct_answer: "6",
    incorrect_answers: ["1", "3", "7"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "The%20idea%20of%20Socialism%20was%20articulated%20and%20advanced%20by%20whom%3F",
    correct_answer: "Karl%20Marx",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "Vladimir%20Lenin",
      "Joseph%20Stalin",
      "Vladimir%20Putin",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "In%20what%20year%20did%20the%20Wall%20Street%20Crash%20take%20place%3F",
    correct_answer: "1929",
    incorrect_answers: ["1932", "1930", "1925"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Which%20one%20of%20these%20tanks%20was%20designed%20and%20operated%20by%20the%20United%20Kingdom%3F",
    correct_answer: "Tog%20II",
    incorrect_answers: ["M4%20Sherman", "Tiger%20H1", "T-34"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "During%20WWII%2C%20in%201945%2C%20the%20United%20States%20dropped%20atomic%20bombs%20on%20the%20two%20Japanese%20cities%20of%20Hiroshima%20and%20what%20other%20city%3F",
    correct_answer: "Nagasaki",
    incorrect_answers: ["Kawasaki", "Tokyo", "Kagoshima"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Which%20of%20the%20following%20African%20countries%20was%20most%20successful%20in%20resisting%20colonization%3F",
    correct_answer: "Ethiopia",
    incorrect_answers: ["C%C3%B4te%20d%E2%80%99Ivoire", "Congo", "Namibia"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Which%20of%20the%20following%20ancient%20peoples%20was%20NOT%20classified%20as%20Hellenic%20%28Greek%29%3F",
    correct_answer: "Illyrians",
    incorrect_answers: ["Dorians", "Achaeans", "Ionians"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Which%20famous%20world%20leader%20is%20famed%20for%20the%20saying%2C%20%22Let%20them%20eat%20cake%22%2C%20yet%20is%20rumored%20that%20he%2Fshe%20never%20said%20it%20at%20all%3F",
    correct_answer: "Marie%20Antoinette",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "Czar%20Nicholas%20II",
      "Elizabeth%20I",
      "Henry%20VIII",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "The%20original%20Roman%20alphabet%20lacked%20the%20following%20letters%20EXCEPT%3A",
    correct_answer: "X",
    incorrect_answers: ["W", "U", "J"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Which%20of%20these%20countries%20remained%20neutral%20during%20World%20War%20II%3F",
    correct_answer: "Switzerland",
    incorrect_answers: ["United%20Kingdom", "France", "Italy"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "What%20was%20Manfred%20von%20Richthofen%27s%20nickname%3F",
    correct_answer: "The%20Red%20Baron",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "The%20High%20Flying%20Ace",
      "The%20Blue%20Serpent%20",
      "The%20Germany%20Gunner",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Which%20modern%20day%20country%20is%20the%20region%20that%20was%20known%20as%20Phrygia%20in%20ancient%20times%3F",
    correct_answer: "Turkey",
    incorrect_answers: ["Syria", "Greece", "Egypt"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "In%20which%20year%20did%20the%20Invasion%20of%20Kuwait%20by%20Iraq%20occur%3F",
    correct_answer: "1990",
    incorrect_answers: ["1992", "1988", "1986"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "When%20did%20the%20Battle%20of%20the%20Somme%20begin%3F",
    correct_answer: "July%201st%2C%201916",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "August%201st%2C%201916",
      "July%202nd%2C%201916",
      "June%2030th%2C%201916",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Who%20was%20the%20first%20president%20of%20the%20United%20States%3F",
    correct_answer: "George%20Washington",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "James%20Madison",
      "Thomas%20Jefferson",
      "James%20K.%20Polk",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "In%201720%2C%20England%20was%20in%20massive%20debt%2C%20and%20became%20in%20involved%20in%20the%20South%20Sea%20Bubble.%20Who%20was%20the%20main%20mastermind%20behind%20it%3F",
    correct_answer: "John%20Blunt",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "Daniel%20Defoe",
      "Robert%20Harley",
      "John%20Churchill",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "When%20was%20Google%20founded%3F",
    correct_answer: "September%204%2C%201998",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "October%209%2C%201997",
      "December%2012%2C%201989",
      "Feburary%207th%2C%202000",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Who%20was%20the%20Prime%20Minister%20of%20Japan%20when%20Japan%20declared%20war%20on%20the%20US%3F",
    correct_answer: "Hideki%20Tojo",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "Michinomiya%20Hirohito",
      "Isoroku%20Yamamoto",
      "Fumimaro%20Konoe",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "What%20was%20the%20first%20sport%20to%20have%20been%20played%20on%20the%20moon%3F",
    correct_answer: "Golf",
    incorrect_answers: ["Football", "Tennis", "Soccer"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "Who%20was%20the%20first%20prime%20minister%20of%20Canada%3F",
    correct_answer: "John%20Macdonald",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "John%20Abbott",
      "Alexander%20Mackenzie",
      "Robert%20Borden",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "How%20was%20Socrates%20executed%3F",
    correct_answer: "Poison",
    incorrect_answers: ["Decapitation", "Firing%20squad", "Crucifixion%20"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "How%20long%20did%20World%20War%20II%20last%3F",
    correct_answer: "6%20years",
    incorrect_answers: ["4%20years", "5%20years", "7%20years"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Which%20of%20the%20following%20countries%20was%20not%20an%20axis%20power%20during%20World%20War%20II%3F",
    correct_answer: "%20Soviet%20Union",
    incorrect_answers: ["Italy", "Germany", "Japan"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "In%201939%2C%20Britain%20and%20France%20declared%20war%20on%20Germany%20after%20it%20invaded%20which%20country%3F",
    correct_answer: "Poland",
    incorrect_answers: ["Czechoslovakia", "Austria", "Hungary"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "The%20%22Trail%20of%20Tears%22%20was%20a%20result%20of%20which%20United%20States%20President%27s%20Indian%20Removal%20Policy%3F",
    correct_answer: "Andrew%20Jackson",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "Harry%20S.%20Truman",
      "Martin%20Van%20Buren",
      "John%20Quincy%20Adams",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Who%20was%20among%20those%20killed%20in%20the%202010%20Smolensk%2C%20Russia%20plane%20crash%20tragedy%3F",
    correct_answer: "The%20Polish%20President",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "Pope%20John%20Paul%20II",
      "Bang-Ding%20Ow",
      "Albert%20Putin",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "To%20what%20political%20party%20did%20Abraham%20Lincoln%20belong%20when%20elected%20POTUS%3F",
    correct_answer: "Republican",
    incorrect_answers: ["Democrat", "Independent", "Whig"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "These%20two%20countries%20held%20a%20commonwealth%20from%20the%2016th%20to%2018th%20century.",
    correct_answer: "Poland%20and%20Lithuania",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "Hutu%20and%20Rwanda",
      "North%20Korea%20and%20South%20Korea",
      "Bangladesh%20and%20Bhutan",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "What%20year%20did%20World%20War%20I%20begin%3F",
    correct_answer: "1914",
    incorrect_answers: ["1905", "1919", "1925"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "How%20old%20was%20Adolf%20Hitler%20when%20he%20died%3F",
    correct_answer: "56",
    incorrect_answers: ["43", "65", "47"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Which%20modern%20country%20is%20known%20as%20%22The%20Graveyard%20of%20Empires%22%3F",
    correct_answer: "Afghanistan",
    incorrect_answers: ["China", "Iraq", "Russia"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "Which%20country%20was%20Josef%20Stalin%20born%20in%3F",
    correct_answer: "Georgia",
    incorrect_answers: ["Russia", "Germany", "Poland"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "Who%20led%20the%20Communist%20Revolution%20of%20Russia%3F",
    correct_answer: "Vladimir%20Lenin",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "Joseph%20Stalin",
      "Vladimir%20Putin",
      "Mikhail%20Gorbachev",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Which%20of%20the%20following%20was%20Brazil%20was%20a%20former%20colony%20under%3F",
    correct_answer: "Portugal",
    incorrect_answers: ["Spain", "The%20Netherlands", "France"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "What%20is%20the%20historical%20name%20of%20Sri%20Lanka%3F",
    correct_answer: "Ceylon",
    incorrect_answers: ["Myanmar", "Colombo", "Badulla"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "In%201453%2C%20which%20important%20city%20fell%3F",
    correct_answer: "Constantinople",
    incorrect_answers: ["Rome", "Hamburg", "Athens"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "What%20was%20the%20name%20commonly%20given%20to%20the%20ancient%20trade%20routes%20that%20connected%20the%20East%20and%20West%20of%20Eurasia%3F",
    correct_answer: "Silk%20Road",
    incorrect_answers: ["Spice%20Road", "Clay%20Road", "Salt%20Road"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "On%20what%20street%20did%20the%201666%20Great%20Fire%20of%20London%20start%3F",
    correct_answer: "Pudding%20Lane",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "Baker%20Street",
      "Houses%20of%20Parliament",
      "St%20Paul%27s%20Cathedral",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question: "In%20what%20year%20was%20the%20M1911%20pistol%20designed%3F",
    correct_answer: "1911",
    incorrect_answers: ["1907", "1899", "1917"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "In%20what%20year%20did%20the%20Great%20Northern%20War%2C%20between%20Russia%20and%20Sweden%2C%20end%3F",
    correct_answer: "1721",
    incorrect_answers: ["1726", "1727", "1724"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "What%20does%20the%20United%20States%20of%20America%20celebrate%20during%20the%204th%20of%20July%3F",
    correct_answer:
      "The%20signing%20of%20the%20Declaration%20of%20Independence",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "The%20anniversary%20of%20the%20Battle%20of%20Gettysburg",
      "The%20crossing%20of%20the%20Delaware%20River",
      "The%20ratification%20of%20the%20Constitution",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Who%20rode%20on%20horseback%20to%20warn%20the%20Minutemen%20that%20the%20British%20were%20coming%20during%20the%20U.S.%20Revolutionary%20War%3F",
    correct_answer: "Paul%20Revere",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "Thomas%20Paine",
      "Henry%20Longfellow",
      "Nathan%20Hale",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Abolitionist%20John%20Brown%20raided%20the%20arsenal%20in%20which%20Virginia%20Town%3F",
    correct_answer: "Harper%27s%20Ferry",
    incorrect_answers: ["Richmond", "Harrisonburg", "Martinsburg"],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "The%20Ottoman%20Empire%20was%20dissolved%20after%20their%20loss%20in%20which%20war%3F",
    correct_answer: "World%20War%20I",
    incorrect_answers: [
      "Crimean%20War",
      "Serbian%20Revolution",
      "Second%20Balkan%20War",
    ],
  },
  {
    category: "History",
    type: "multiple",
    difficulty: "easy",
    question:
      "Which%20famous%20military%20commander%20marched%20an%20army%2C%20which%20included%20war%20elephants%2C%20over%20the%20Alps%20during%20the%20Second%20Punic%20War%3F",
    correct_answer: "Hannibal",
    incorrect_answers: ["Garmanicus", "Alexander%20the%20Great", "Tiberius"],
  },
];